readingeggs.com.au 2019-06-21

# Privacy Policy – ABC Reading Eggs

This Privacy Policy describes how Blake eLearning (ABN 64 140 998 821), including its related companies which handle personal information (Company), collects, holds, uses and discloses personal information consistent with the Australian Privacy Act 1988.

Blake eLearning is committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information. An individual who provides personal information to the Company, either directly or through a business partner or service provider, has ready access to this Policy.

By providing personal information to the Company and having access to this Policy, either directly or through a business partner or service provider, an individual consents to the Company collecting, holding, using and disclosing personal information in accordance with this Policy.

## What information do we collect and how do we use it?

### Free trial registration

When you sign up for a free trial of ABC Reading Eggs, ABC Reading Eggs Junior, ABC Reading Eggspress and ABC Mathseeds, we collect your first and last name, email address, phone number, your country and postcode. Once you log into your free trial account, we also collect your child’s first and last name and their date of birth. Collection of these details is necessary for us to tailor our communications to you, manage your child’s progress through the programs, and ensure we can better respond to your customer service requests. You are entitled to provide us with a pseudonym if you wish to sign up anonymously. If you choose to sign up anonymously you will still have full access to the trial and all its features.

### Subscription and product purchases

When you subscribe to ABC Reading Eggs, ABC Reading Eggs Junior, ABC Reading Eggspress or ABC Mathseeds, or purchase any of our products, we collect your first and last name and your credit card details. If you are purchasing one of our products, we also collect your address for delivery. When you subscribe or purchase a product, we do not allow the option for you to use a pseudonym as we require this information for payment and/or delivery.

### Surveys

Our surveys are designed to collect your feedback so that we can improve our programs and the way we market to you. When you complete one of our surveys, we may collect your first and last name, your email address, your home address if the survey entitles you to a free gift, your child's age, your income, as well as your opinion or other personal information relating to our survey questions. You are not obliged to complete any of our surveys, either as part of our free trial or subscription programs or otherwise. You are entitled to provide us with a pseudonym if you wish to complete our surveys anonymously, although if completion of our survey entitles you to a free gift, we will require your correct name and address details to deliver it to you.

### Social media

We periodically run competitions through the Website and our social media channels. By entering into a competition, you acknowledge that we may use your personal information for the purposes of administering the competition and to contact you about our products and services.

We may also provide you with joint promotional offers in conjunction with other third parties. These offers are designed to be relevant to you, but should you not wish to receive this, you may select the 'Unsubscribe' link at the bottom of every email we send you. Alternatively you may contact us at [dpo@blake.com.au](mailto:dpo@blake.com.au).

### Cookies

Like many websites, we use cookies to enhance your experience and gather information about visitors and visits to our websites. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognise your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

We may contract third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business.

You can choose to have your web browser (like Google Chrome or Internet Explorer) warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you turn cookies off, you won't have access to many features that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly. However, you can still place orders over the telephone by contacting our customer service team.

### Email communications

All Blake eLearning email communications are in accordance with the Spam Act 2003. When you sign up for a free trial, you will automatically receive promotional and student report emails from ABC Reading Eggs, ABC Reading Eggs Junior, ABC Reading Eggspress and ABC Mathseeds. To opt out of these email communications, you can click on the 'Unsubscribe' link at the bottom of the email, or you can simply log into your account and click on the 'My Account' option, where you can choose to opt in or out of emails.

Also, if you have opted in to receive the ABC Shop newsletter on new releases from the ABC Shop, the Australian Broadcasting Corporation may send you periodic emails. If you would no longer like to receive these promotional emails, you may unsubscribe at any time by following the aforementioned instructions. Please note that due to email production schedules, upon cancellation you may receive any emails already in production.

### Data storage and security

#### Limiting access to education records

Education records are only accessible to users who are logged in and have been successfully authenticated by entering a username and password. Students are only able to access their own progress, and teachers can only view students from within their school.

Student and teacher data can only be accessed by Blake eLearning staff and partners. Data is never shared with third parties without explicit permission.

#### Management of historical data

When a subscription to the application expires, we retain the data in our database. If the school would like this data to be deleted, they can contact our customer service team and we will be happy to oblige.

#### Challenging the accuracy of student or teacher data

If a teacher believes there is a problem with any data that has been collected, they can contact our customer service team and we will investigate the matter. If a problem is identified, we will seek a solution to fix it.

#### Ensuring data is secure and protected

Student and teacher data is stored in a secure database on Amazon Web Services (AWS). Access to these servers is limited to the application, and by software developers at Blake eLearning, via secure shell.

Passwords for users of the system are encrypted using salt and hash technologies.

All data transferred within ABC Reading Eggs, ABC Reading Eggs Junior, ABC Reading Eggspress and ABC Mathseeds is protected by SSL. SSL is a technology that makes your data illegible in transit. If anyone were to intercept communication between our servers and your computer, they would not be able to easily decipher what was being passed back and forth.

## Disclosure of information to third parties

Blake eLearning does not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer your personal information to third party sources. The term 'third party sources' does not include Blake eLearning's related companies. 

It also does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising or other uses.

## Overseas disclosure

Some of the organisations to which the Company will disclose personal information are located outside Australia. By accessing the website or opening an email on which this Policy is located or linked, the individual is directed to read it and as a result, giving consent to the collection, handling, use and disclosure of personal information by the Company in accordance with this Policy. One of the things the individual consents to is that the Company is not required to ensure that an overseas recipient of personal information complies with the Australian Privacy Act 1988 (see Australian Privacy Principle 8.1 by going to http://www.oaic.gov.au/).

## Third party links

In an attempt to provide you with increased value, we may include third party links on our site. These linked sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these linked sites (including if a specific link does not work).

## Changes to our privacy policy

We may change, modify, or revise this Privacy Policy in order to comply with any applicable laws, to reflect changes in our processes or for any other reason at any time. Material changes in our Privacy Policy will be communicated to you, but we also encourage you to check our Privacy Policy periodically to read about any changes, modifications, or revisions. You will be deemed to have consented to any variations by your continued use of the Websites or Platforms following any changes being made.

## Terms of use

Please also visit our Terms of Use section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website.

## Access to and correction of personal information

Blake eLearning will take reasonable steps to ensure that all your personal information it holds is accurate, up-to-date and relevant. You can request access to, corrections of, or erasure of your personal information held by Blake eLearning, or object to the use of your personal information by us, by contacting our Data Protection and Privacy Officer at [dpo@blake.com.au](mailto:dpo@blake.com.au).

In addition to the above, you also have the right to delete, restrict processing or change your personal information online. To change or delete your personal information, simply log into your account and click on the 'My Account' tab, where you can remove or change your address, or change your name, email and/or phone number. If you wish to restrict processing or delete all your information, please contact the Data Protection and Privacy Officer.

## If information or consent is not provided

Without all of the required personal information being provided or consent being given, the Company will not be able to provide the product or service an individual is seeking, and may not be able to handle enquiries or claims in connection with those products or services.

## Contact us

All requests to access, update and delete personal data as well as questions and concerns about your personal data and this Privacy Policy should be directed to the Blake eLearning Data Protection and Privacy Officer at [dpo@blake.com.au](mailto:dpo@blake.com.au). We will endeavour to respond to your query as quickly as possible.

**Blake eLearning Privacy Officer:**  
Ph: (02) 8585 4067  
Email: [dpo@blake.com.au](mailto:dpo@blake.com.au)  
Address: 655 Parramatta Rd Leichhardt NSW 2040

## Your consent

When an individual accesses the website or opens an email on which this Privacy Policy and Notification is located or linked, the individual is directed to read it. As a result, the individual is notified of the matters that the Company must notify and consents to the collection, handling, use and disclosure of personal information by the Company in accordance with this Policy.

This website is published by Blake Publishing, with support from 3P Learning.

The ABC Connect trademark is used under license by the Australian Broadcasting Corporation.

This Privacy Statement has been developed in accordance with the Australian Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and the Privacy Amendment (Enhancing Privacy Protection) Act 2012 (Cth), the New Zealand Privacy Act 1993, the United Kingdom Data Protection Act 1998 and the United States Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act and Rule as administered by the Federal Trade Commission.

Policy last updated: 7 February 2019
